A Guide to the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial records FA061
Rockefeller Archive Center
Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial records
1918-1949
Rockefeller Archive Center
Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial
FA061
53.43 Cubic Feet 141 document cases
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged in five series, as follows:
Series 1 - Minutes and Dockets Series 2 - Administration Series 3 - Appropriations Series 4 - FinancesSeries 1016 - Photographs
Biographical/Historical note
The Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial was incorporated in October 1918, for general philanthropic purposes. It was not geographically limited and indeed was international, especially in its early emphasis on emergency relief. A memorial to Laura Spelman Rockefeller, the first thought for a program was the welfare of women and children, but philanthropy is not easily granted along divisions of age or sex and so for the first few years of the Memorial's existence the program was fluid. W. S. Richardson was the main executive during the years 1918-1922. The Memorial worked through John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s office then, and many of the Memorial files were interwoven with other office files.
In 1922 Beardsley Ruml became director of the Memorial and a long-range program was developed. Appropriations were still made in the areas of leisure, public health, and emergency relief, but from 1922 through the end of the Memorial's independent existence, the social sciences and welfare, child study and parent education, and interracial relations became primary interests. Research was sponsored, but not as an end unto itself; grants were made for demonstrations, concrete applications of newly gained knowledge. The aim of the entire program was to achieve concrete improvement in the conditions of life and to contribute realistically to public welfare.
On January 3, 1929, the Memorial consolidated with The Rockefeller Foundation and became its division of Social Sciences. A final grant of $10,000,000 was made to the Spelman Fund of New York, an independently incorporated board, to administer some appropriations in child study, parent education, and interracial relations. The Spelman Fund went on to continue the Memorial's fledgling interest in public administration as its main emphasis.
The collection is incomplete, yet it includes many strays from other collections. For the early years of the program, 1918-1922, materials should also be found in the Rockefeller Family Archives. Strays from John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Advisory Committee, of which some grants were eventually taken over by the Memorial, are also included in the collection. The main Advisory Committee file is in the Rockefeller Family Archives. The entire Spelman Fund series in interracial relations, child study, and parent education were merged with the Memorial files at the termination of the Spelman Fund. There is some Rockefeller Foundation correspondence included for the grants that were administered by The Rockefeller Foundation after 1929. These strays are so noted in the inventory.
The Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial Collection covers the period from 1918-1949.
Scope and Contents note
Important subjects in this collection include: child development and parent education; public health; interracial relations; general education; foreign and home missions; emergency relief in time of natural disaster and war; development of social sciences - both practically and theoretically; and social welfare.
Among the correspondents are: Charles H. Brent; Kenneth Chorley; Edmund E. Day; Katherine B. Davis; Cleveland E. Dodge; Edwin Embree; Abraham Flexner; Guy Stanton Ford; Raymond B. Fosdick; Lawrence K. Frank; Ernest M. Hopkins; Charles Evans Hughes; Charles Merriam; Starr Murphy; George W. Murphy; W. S. Richardson; John D. Rockefeller, Sr.; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; Beardsley Ruml; Sydnor H. Walker; and Arthur Woods.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IV 2B 04
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The papers of the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial were deposited with The Rockefeller Foundation Archives in 1929 by the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Public welfare; Social sciences -- History; Disaster relief; United States; Race and society; Public health; Parenting -- Study and teaching; Child development; Race relations; Education; Missions; Missions -- United States
- Minutes and Dockets, 1918-1928; 1
  - Dockets, 1919-1921 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dockets, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dockets, January-April 1923 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dockets, May-June 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dockets, November-December 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dockets, January-February 1924 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dockets, March-April 1924 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dockets, May-June 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dockets, July-October 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dockets, November-December 1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dockets, January-February 1925 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dockets, March 1925 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Dockets, April-May 1925 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Dockets, June 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dockets, July-October 1925 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Dockets, November 1925 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Dockets, December 1925 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Dockets, January-February 1926 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Dockets, March-April 1926 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Dockets, May 1926 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Dockets, June-October 1926 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Dockets, November 1926 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Dockets, December 1926 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Dockets, January-February 1927 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Dockets, March 1927 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Dockets, April-May 1927 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Dockets, May 24-31, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Dockets, June-October 1927 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Dockets, November 1927 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Dockets, December 1927 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Dockets, January-February 1928 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Dockets, March 1928 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Dockets, April 1928 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Dockets, May 1928 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Dockets, June-October 1928 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Dockets, November 1928 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Dockets, December 1928 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1919-1920 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1921-1922 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1923-1924 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1918-1920 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1921-1922 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1923-1925 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1926-1928 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Leonard Outhwaite History of the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Minutes Index, 2 box(es) 3.5x5x12 inches each.
    General
    Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial minutes index provides indexing to the LSRM's minutes, which are found in Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial records (FA061), Series 1: Minutes and Dockets, box 5.
    Scope and Contents
    The index includes entries for personal names and organizations, not subject terms or geographic places. Citations to the LSRM's minutes appear on the left edge of the cards as a 5-digit number, composed of the year and page number. For instance: "25123" = 1925, page 123.
    Arrangement
    The index is arranged alphabetically.
    - A - L (Box 6)
    - M - Z (Box 7)
- Administration, 1918-1933; 2
  Arrangement note
  Folders in this series are arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains information on trustees and staff, clippings, official documents, history and consolidation, general policy, correspondence, and staff meetings.
  - Advisory Committee, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report and Final Report, 1918-1929, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bertheau, R. C., 1924-1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brent, Charles, 1922-1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bylaws (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Certificates of Incorporation (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Consent of Board to Action, 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1923-1928 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1923-1928 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1923-1928 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dashiell, L. M., 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Day, Edmund E., 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Debevoise, Thomas, 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Director's Reports, 1919-1928 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Director's Reports, 1919-1928 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Dodge, Cleveland, 1922-1926 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Documents of Consolidation, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Dunham, L. B., 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Ford, Guy S., 1925-1933 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Fosdick, Raymond, 1921-1928 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Frank, Lawrence K., 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hopkins, Ernest, 1924-1933 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Hughes, Charles Evans, 1918-1933 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - International Education Board, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Lee, Ivy, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Murphy, Starr, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Murray, George W., 1918-1926 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Myers, Louis G., 1919-1924 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Peterson, Leroy, 1926-1928 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Policy, 1921-1929 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Prospective Members, 1919-1921 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Publicity (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Reorganization, 1926-1928 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Richardson, W. S., 1919-1929 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1919-1928 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1926-1928 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - European Office, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Ruml, Beardsley, 1922-1933 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Staff Meetings, 1924-1928 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Staff Meetings, 1924-1928 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Staff Meetings, 1924-1928 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Stanley, Frank, 1925-1927 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Stubbs, F. B., 1923-1925 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Trustees, 1922-1928 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Walker, S. H., 1925-1929 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Woods, Arthur, 1922-1927 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Annual Reports (1919-1928) and Final Report (1933), 1919-1928, 1933 (Box 40, Folder 48)
- Appropriations, 1917-1949; 3
  This series is arranged in ten subseries, as follows:
  Subseries 1 - Public Health
  Subseries 2 - Religious
  Subseries 3 - Emergency Relief
  Subseries 4 - Leisure
  Subseries 5 - Child Study and Parent Education
  Subseries 6 - Social Studies
  Subseries 7 - Social Welfare
  Subseries 8 - Interracial Relations
  Subseries 9 - General Education
  Subseries 10 - Miscellaneous
  Existence and Location of Copies
  Scholarly access to original archival material is permitted. User copies of microfilm are also available. The Appropriations series is reproduced in the microfilm publication of The Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial Collection, Series III: Appropriations, 1917-1945, 89 reels (distributed by Scholarly Resources Inc.).
  This series contains folders for individual appropriations as well as general subject information, declinations, and folders for particular individuals. Material included consists of correspondence, charts, maps, books, clippings, reports, pamphlets, and photographs. Books have been filed in the Archives library, and photographs have been included in the photograph collection.
  LSRM appropriations have no extra notation. Appropriations that were subsequently administered by either The Rockefeller Foundation or the Spelman Fund of New York are noted LSRM-RF or LSRM-SF. Appropriations administered exclusively by the Spelman Fund are noted SF. Advisory Committee is designated as such. When the request was fulfilled by the Memorial, it is noted Advisory Committee-LSRM.
  Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial Appropriations Index
  A card index to the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial records, Series 3: Appropriations, Subseries 3.1 3.10 is available for researcher use. The LSRM Appropriations Index does not distinguish between these 10 subseries, each with its own A-Z arrangement. After using the index to identify a file title, users should check within each relevant subseries (or all 10) to locate the indexed file titles. LSRM files are indicated by the file title listed under the index heading on each card.
  The LSRM Appropriations Index is located in drawers 56-58 of the 72-drawer cabinet next to the RAC's reading room.
  - Appropriations - Public Health, 3_01
    - American Child Health Association, 1922-1928 (Box 1, Folder 1, Reel 1, Frame 0003)
      Merger of ACHA with Child Health Association. General budget. Demonstrations, interpreting and applying facts of public health research. Advisory capacity and promotion of child health. Herbert Hoover.
    - American Child Health Association, 1922-1928 (Box 1, Folder 2, Reel 1, Frame 0003)
    - American Child Health Association - Survey, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3, Reel 1, Frame 0140)
      Follow-up on 86 city survey; general background information.
    - American Child Hygiene Association, 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 4, Reel 1, Frame 0160)
      Research, education, cooperation with other organizations. Prenatal, infant, and preschool child; general background information, Herbert Hoover.
    - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 5, Reel 1, Frame 0202)
      Films, cancer week.
    - Association for the Improvement of Conditions of the Poor, 1919-1925 (Box 1, Folder 6, Reel 1, Frame 0223)
      General budget.
    - Bellevue Hospital, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 7, Reel 1, Frame 0364)
      Tuberculosis division - day camp.
    - Brooklyn Bureau of Charities - Tuberculosis, 1920-1928 (Box 1, Folder 8, Reel 1, Frame 0378)
    - Child Health Organization, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 9, Reel 1, Frame 0500)
      Budget.
    - East Harlem Health Center, 1924-1931 (Box 1, Folder 10, Reel 1, Frame 0548)
      LSRM-RF. Coordinating unit for social agencies and Department of Health; general background information.
    - East Harlem Health Center, 1924-1931 (Box 1, Folder 11, Reel 1, Frame 0548)
    - East Harlem Health Center - Nursing Demonstration, 1921-1928 (Box 1, Folder 12, Reel 1, Frame 0670)
      Child hygiene, tuberculosis, other communicable diseases. Demonstration for student public health nurses. Bailey Burrit.
    - East Harlem Health Center - Nursing Demonstration, 1921-1928 (Box 1, Folder 13, Reel 1, Frame 0670)
    - Henry Street Settlement, 1919-1944 (Box 2, Folder 14, Reel 1, Frame 0856)
      LSRM-RF. Visiting nurse service. Endowment.
    - Joint Vocational Service, 1926-1931 (Box 2, Folder 15, Reel 1, Frame 0944)
      LSRM-RF. Combined bureau for American Association of Social Workers and National Organization of Public Health Nurses.
    - Judson Health Center, 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 16, Reel 1, Frame 1046)
      Judson Memorial Church - clinic for women and children. Remodeling and general background information.
    - League of Red Cross Societies - Junior Red Cross, 1922-1929 (Box 2, Folder 17-20, Reel 1, Frame 1091, Reel 2, Frame 0003)
      LSRM-RF. Secretariat, information center, study bureau. T. B. Kittredge.
      Related Archival Materials note
      Photographs removed to RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1016, Box 2, Folder 15.
    - League of Red Cross Societies - Junior Red Cross - Pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 21, Reel 2, Frame 0344)
    - Lincoln Hospital and Home, 1920-1926 (Box 2, Folder 22, Reel 2, Frame 0531)
      Training school for colored nurses.
    - Lincoln Hospital and Home, 1920-1926 (Box 2, Folder 23, Reel 2, Frame 0531)
    - Massachusetts Department of Mental Diseases, 1927-1934 (Box 3, Folder 24, Reel 2, Frame 0715)
      LSRM-RF. Survey of insane, epileptic, and mentally defective in Massachusetts institutions.
    - Massachusetts Department of Mental Diseases - Reports (Box 3, Folder 25, Reel 2, Frame 0802)
    - Massachusetts Society for Mental Hygiene, 1925-1929 (Box 3, Folder 26, Reel 2, Frame 0952)
      LSRM-RF. Research in social and economic aspects of mental disorder.
    - Maternity Center Association - Brooklyn, 1920-1929 (Box 3, Folder 27, Reel 2, Frame 1018)
      LSRM-RF. Maternal education by demonstration stations. Mothercraft Club.
    - Maternity Center Association - Brooklyn, 1920-1929 (Box 3, Folder 28, Reel 2, Frame 1018)
    - Maternity Center Association - Brooklyn, 1920-1929 (Box 3, Folder 29, Reel 2, Frame 1018)
    - Maternity Center Association - Brooklyn - Reports (Box 3, Folder 30, Reel 2, Frame 1246, Reel 3, Frame 0004)
    - Maternity Center Association - Manhattan, 1919-1926 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      Demonstrations, training public health nurses, ambulatory clinics.
    - Maternity Center Association - Manhattan, 1919-1926 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Maternity Center Association - Manhattan, 1919-1926 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Maternity Center Association - Manhattan, 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Maternity Center Association - Report (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Mescal, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      Drug used by Indians in Oklahoma in religious ceremonies - "peyote."
    - National Child Health Council, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      Coordination in child health field.
    - National Health Council, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - National Hospital for Speech Disorders, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, 1921-1928 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      General background information. Clearing house for all information relating to public health nursing - library service, vocational and advisory. William H. Welch.
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, 1921-1928 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing - Pamphlets (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - National Tuberculosis Association, 1923-1926 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - New Haven Nursery School, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - New York Academy of Medicine, 1921-1925 (Box 4, Folder 45)
      Study of child health work in New York City.
    - New York Milk Committee, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 46)
      Milk supply, infant mortality, maternity center work, general background information.
    - New York State Society for the Promotion of Occupational Therapy, 1920-1921 (Box 4, Folder 47)
      Demonstration center - mental, physical and economic benefits in hospital, home, and workshop, general background information.
    - New York Tuberculosis Association, 1920-1928 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      Educational, preventative, Christmas Seal, vocational service, demonstration, general background information.
      Photographs removed to RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1016, Box 2, Folder 16.
    - New York Tuberculosis Association, 1920-1928 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Psychiatric Research Foundation, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 50)
      New York City.
    - Reconstruction Hospital, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Sheppard and Enoch Pratt Hospital, 1926-1928 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Society of Friends, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Society of the New York Hospital, 1928-1933 (Box 5, Folder 54)
      LSRM-RF. Lying-in hospital.
    - State Charities Aid Association - Mental Hygiene, 1927-1931 (Box 5, Folder 55)
      LSRM-RF. Statistical study of records of mental disorder of the New York State Hospital Commission.
    - State Charities Aid Association - Mental Hygiene, 1927-1931 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Stony Wold Sanatorium, 1920-1921 (Box 5, Folder 57)
      Lake Kushaqua, New York. General background information, tuberculosis, deficit.
    - Union Hospital, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 58)
      Bronx, New York.
    - United Hospital Fund of New York, 1919-1929 (Box 5, Folder 59)
      Free services for sick poor, promote accurate and uniform statistics, collect funds, general background information.
    - University Hospital of Cleveland, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Vanderbilt University - Public Health, 1925-1926 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Victory Memorial Hospital, 1922-1927 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Visiting Nurse Association of Brooklyn, 1919-1923 (Box 5, Folder 63)
      General background information.
    - Volunteer Service, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Appropriations - Religious, 3_02
    - American Baptist Foreign Mission Society, 1925-1928 (Box 6, Folder 65)
      General background information, endowment.
    - American Baptist Home Mission Society, 1925-1929 (Box 6, Folder 66)
      General background information, stocks.
    - Baptist Church Extension Society, 1919-1920 (Box 6, Folder 67)
      Sunday school, women's auxiliary, assistance for English-speaking churches in general work, foreign churches, general background information.
    - Baptist Missionary Convention, 1919-1925 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Baptist Union of Western Canada, 1919-1925 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - China Continuation Committee, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 70)
      Building fund, Shanghai.
    - Commission on Relations with France and Belgium, 1921-1922 (Box 6, Folder 71)
      U.S. Protestant churches, aid war damaged, reconstruction of churches, foreign missions, education of religious leaders, general background information, William Sloane Coffin.
    - European Protestant Churches, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 72)
      Advisory Committee.
    - Moro Education Foundation, 1922-1923 (Box 6, Folder 73)
      Christian good will to Muslims in the Philippines via education. Charles H. Brent.
    - National Christian Council of China, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - National Council on Religion in Higher Education, 1923-1929 (Box 6, Folder 75)
      LSRM-RF Fellowships.
    - National Council on Religion in Higher Education, 1923-1929 (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - National Council on Religion in Higher Education, 1923-1929 (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - National Council on Religion in Higher Education - Report (Box 6, Folder 78)
    - New York City Baptist Mission Society (Box 6, Folder 79)
      English-speaking schools, foreign churches and missions, general background information.
    - Northern Baptist Convention, 1923-1924 (Box 6, Folder 80)
      Toward Fund - General Board of Promotion.
    - Reformed Church Pension Fund, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - Riverside Church, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 82)
      Trust Fund - memorial.
    - University of Chicago - Chapel, 1928-1929 (Box 7, Folder 83)
      Endowment.
    - Woman's American Baptist Foreign Mission Society, 1919-1929 (Box 7, Folder 84)
      Jubilee Fund, Women's Christian Colleges in the Orient. Lucy Peabody.
    - Woman's American Baptist Foreign Mission Society, 1919-1929 (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - Woman's American Baptist Foreign Mission Society, 1919-1929 (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - Woman's American Baptist Foreign Mission Society, 1919-1929 (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - Woman's American Baptist Foreign Mission Society, 1919-1929 (Box 7, Folder 88)
    - Woman's American Baptist Foreign Mission Society - Pamphlets (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - Woman's American Baptist Home Mission Society, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 90)
      Toward permanent fund.
  - Appropriations - Emergency Relief, 3_03
    - American Red Cross - Bulgarian Relief, 1926-1928 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - American Red Cross - Japanese Relief, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - American Red Cross - Russian Refugees, 1927-1928 (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - American Relief Administration - Russian Refugees, 1922-1924 (Box 8, Folder 94)
      Constantinople.